questions:
- number: 1
  question: 'An aircraft fitted with a piston engine must be filled with:'
  answers:
    a: 'AVTUR fuel.'
    b: 'Unleaded Fuel.'
    c: 'Leaded Fuel.'
    d: 'MOGAS.'
    e: 'AVGAS.'
  points: 1
- number: 2
  question: 'What colour is AVGAS 100LL'
  answers:
    a: 'Clear or Straw Colour.'
    b: 'Blue.'
    c: 'Red or Purple.'
    d: 'Green.'
  points: 1
- number: 3
  question: 'The carburettor heat can be used as:'
  answers:
    a: 'an anti-icing action (ice prevention).'
    b: 'a de-icing action (ice removal).'
    c: 'an alternative supply of air to the engine.'
    d: 'all of the above.'
  points: 1
- number: 4
  question: 'Should ice form on your carburettor and you have a small 
    reduction in MP, rpm, or air-speed, you should'
  answers:
    a: 'keep adjusting the power by opening the throttle.'
    b: 'apply carburettor heat, full-on.'
    c: 'use alternate static.'
  points: 1
- number: 5
  question: 'Ice that forms on the engine air filter is known as:'
  answers:
    a: 'throttle ice.'
    b: 'fuel evaporation ice.'
    c: 'impact ice.'
  points: 1
- number: 6
  question: 'What common action should be taken if impact or throttle icing occurs?'
  answers:
    a: 'Reduce power.'
    b: 'Increase power.'
    c: 'Apply carburettor heat.'
    d: 'Warm the engine.'
  points: 1
- number: 7
  question: 'After flying for some time, the centre-zero ammeter shows almost zero 
    (just a small positive indication). This would mean:'
  answers:
    a: 'that the alternator has failed and the battery is providing all the power.'
    b: 'insufficient electrical output is being produced by the alternator.'
    c: 'that the battery is being recharged.'
    d: 'that the battery is fully charged and the system is working normally.'
  points: 1
- number: 8
  question: 'If the alternator fails, the electrical system will receive power from:'
  answers:
    a: 'an emergency generator.'
    b: 'the battery.'
    c: 'a wind-driven electrical generating device.'
  points: 1
- number: 9
  question: 'Should the alternator fail and the battery power being consumed:'
  answers:
    a: 'the engine driven fuel pump would stop working.'
    b: 'the fuel boost pump would still be available.'
    c: 'most of the engine instruments would stop working.'
    d: 'the engine would malfunction.'
  points: 1
- number: 10
  question: 'Excessive priming of an engine can:'
  answers:
    a: 'cause the spark to occur at the incorrect time.'
    b: 'increase the risk of manifold fire during start.'
    c: 'reduce the amount of fuel available in the manifold.'
    d: 'adversely effect the the oil pressure.'
  points: 1
- number: 11
  question: 'Aircraft fuel tanks require a vent, the purpose of which is to:'
  answers:
    a: 'avoid build up of dangerous fumes.'
    b: 'allow condensation inside the tank to escape.'
    c: 'allow the pressure inside the tank to equalise with the outside pressure.'
  points: 1
- number: 12
  question: 'Aircraft spark plugs may become fouled with a build-up of lead from 
    the fuel, if the engine is operated for any length of time at a:'
  answers:
    a: 'high power setting with lean mixture.'
    b: 'low power setting with a lean mixture.'
    c: 'high power setting with a rich mixture.'
    d: 'low power setting with a rich mixture.'
  points: 1
- number: 13
  question: 'If you set the altimeter to QNH, the instrument should read:'
  answers:
    a: 'zero feet.'
    b: 'density altitude.'
    c: 'pressure altitude.'
    d: 'vertical distance AMSL.'
  points: 1
- number: 14
  question: 'The red radial line on the airspeed indicator represents the:'
  answers:
    a: 'structural cruising speed.'
    b: 'landing gear lowered speed.'
    c: 'normal operating speed range.'
    d: 'never exceed speed.'
  points: 1
- number: 15
  question: 'Rotation about the longitudinal axis is referred to as:'
  answers:
    a: 'yawing, and is effected by the rudder.'
    b: 'yawing, and is effected by the ailerons.'
    c: 'rolling, and is effected by the ailerons.'
    d: 'pitching, and is effected by the elevator.'
  points: 1
- number: 16
  question: 'The tendency of an aircraft to return to its original condition 
    when disturbed from straight and level flight is know as:'
  answers:
    a: 'controllability.'
    b: 'manoeuverability.'
    c: 'stability.'
    d: 'balance.'
  points: 1
- number: 17
  question: 'During a climbing turn you must be careful of:'
  answers:
    a: 'the tendency to over-bank the aircraft as the horizon is not always obvious.'
    b: 'decreasing yor rate of climb.'
    c: 'the tendency to under-bank the aircraft as the horizon is not always obvious.'
  points: 1
- number: 18
  question: "How is the aircraft's performance affected by mud or minor damage on 
    the surface of the wings?"
  answers:
    a: 'Lift is decreased, drag is decreased.'
    b: 'Lift is increased, drag is decreased.'
    c: 'Lift is increased, drag is increased.'
    d: 'Lift is decreased, drag is increased.'
  points: 1
- number: 19
  question: 'A blockage of the static system would likely be corrected by applying:'
  answers:
    a: 'alternate air on.'
    b: 'pitot heat on.'
    c: 'alternate static on.'
    d: 'carburettor heat on.'
  points: 1
- number: 20
  question: 'During your take-off roll, the airspeed indicator remains at zero. 
    You should:'
  answers:
    a: 'abort the take-off.'
    b: 'try to work out why the ASI is not working.'
    c: 'estimate your rotate speed.'
    d: 'select alternate static and pitot heat on.'
  points: 1
- number: 21
  question: 'If after landing, you find one brake is not working, you should:'
  answers:
    a: 'stop on the runway.'
    b: 'taxi back to the tarmac parking as the nosewheel will still be functional.'
    c: 'allow your aircraft to slow using most of the runway, taxi clear of the runway, 
      and radio for assistance on the ground frequency.'
  points: 1
- number: 22
  question: 'For proper internal cooling, the engine must have:'
  answers:
    a: 'a functioning oil cooler thermostat.'
    b: 'a correctly leaned mixture setting.'
    c: 'circulating oil at a pressure within the permissible range.'
    d: 'proper airflow over the exhaust manifold.'
  points: 1
- number: 23
  question: 'If you encounter gusting wind in the circuit, what speed would you 
    try to maintain on the final approach?'
  answers:
    a: 'About 5kt above the stall to minimise the impact of the gusts.'
    b: 'Normal approach speed because it is chosed to account for such conditions.'
    c: "About 5 to 10 kt above the normal approach speed depending on the 
      strengths of the gusts."
    d: 'Manouvre speed.'
  points: 1
- number: 24
  question: 'After start, engine oil pressure must reach normal operating pressure 
    (the green sector) within:'
  answers:
    a: '30 minutes.'
    b: '10 minutes.'
    c: '15 seconds.'
    d: '30 seconds.'
  points: 1
- number: 25
  question: "While taxiing, you notice another aircraft is approaching you on the same  
    taxiway from the opposite direction. Should you:"
  answers:
    a: 'continue straight ahead and be prepared to stop.'
    b: 'move to the left and stop if necessary.'
    c: 'move to the right and stop if necessary.'
    d: 'stop immediately.'
  points: 1
- number: 26
  question: 'An aircraft will stall:'
  answers:
    a: 'at a higher speed if power is increased.'
    b: 'at the same indicated airspeed as altitude increases.'
    c: "when the aircraft's weight exceeds lift"
    d: 'at a lower indicated airspeed as altitude decreases.'
  points: 1
- number: 27
  question: 'When comparing the hazards of wake turbulence, the wingtip vortices 
    trailing behind large aeroplanes in flight:'
  answers:
    a: 'will present no hazard when the vortices are encountered in level 
      cruising flight.'
    b: 'will increase in intensity and violence as the speed of the large 
      aeroplane increases'
    c: 'are most severe when the large aeroplane is at low speed during 
      climbs or approaches for landings.'
  points: 1
- number: 28
  question: 'For proper cooling the engine must have:'
  answers:
    a: 'the correct mixture setting for that operation.'
    b: 'the correct quantity of oil in the engine.'
    c: 'the correct amount of cooling airflow around the engine.'
    d: 'all of the above.'
  points: 1
- number: 29
  question: 'Detonation occurs in a reciprocating engine when:'
  answers:
    a: 'a spark plug is fouled and shorts out.'
    b: 'the mixture is too rich.'
    c: 'the charge explodes instead of just burning.'
    d: 'hot spots ignite the mixture too soon.'
  points: 1
- number: 30
  question: 'Although the master switch is off, before leaving an aircraft a 
    pilot most also ensure that the magneto switch is off. The reason for this is:'
  answers:
    a: 'the magneto system is independent of the aircraft power and the engine 
      could start if the propeller is turned.'
    b: 'so the key can be removed.'
    c: 'the magneto system will have no earth and cannot be energised.'
    d: 'so the battery will not discharge overnight.'
  points: 1


solutions:
  1: c
  2: b
  3: d
  4: b
  5: c
  6: c
  7: d
  8: b
  9: c
  10: b
  11: c
  12: d
  13: d
  14: d
  15: c
  16: c
  17: a
  18: d
  19: c
  20: a
  21: c
  22: c
  23: c
  24: d
  25: c
  26: b
  27: c
  28: d
  29: c
  30: a
